<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nothing Owned</title><link>https://ydzhou.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Nothing Owned</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ydzhou.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A simple terminal text editor written in Go</title><link>https://ydzhou.github.io/tech/2021-01-07-ste/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ydzhou.github.io/tech/2021-01-07-ste/</guid><description>&lt;p>I build a simple text editor in the terminal &lt;a href="https://github.com/ydzhou/ste">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Similar to MVC pattern, a text editor has three independent modules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>controller: to handle customer keyboard input and dispatch for further processing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>model: to store what customer is working on and process necessary business logic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>view: to render user interface of the editor&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ydzhou.github.io/ste0.svg" alt="Overview">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can think of the editor is in an infinite loop. First we clear the screen and render the viewable text document content in &lt;code>stdout&lt;/code>. The content view is decided by the position of the cursor and the size of the terminal screen. Then we listen on the key input at &lt;code>stdin&lt;/code> in order to modify the text document or execute corresponding commands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flatdom, a civilization simulator</title><link>https://ydzhou.github.io/tech/2015-02-23-flatdom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ydzhou.github.io/tech/2015-02-23-flatdom/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why">Why？&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Any civilization is evitably strangled in a process where it starts with exploring into the wild land, then settling, developing to its most high, and eventually fallen by the warfare or other misfortune. I am deeply curious about such process and try to simulate it. For simplicity, there are only three types of events in Flatdom, exploration, development and war.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-flatdom">What is Flatdom?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Flatdom is a 2-dimensional world. The world consists of many grids. Every grids can either be a settlement for the Flatone, the Flatdom people; or a wild land, waiting for our brave explorer. Flatone will keep exploring the neighboring grids and developing the existing settlement. There are many factions among Flatdom people and they wage war to fight for the grid.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://ydzhou.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ydzhou.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am living in a small nordic town by the Pudget Sound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been coding since I was a boy and my passion never fades. My first programming language is LOGO. Til today, I still remember myself got confused every time when trying to figure out where the little turtle would land.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I detoured to the field of embedded programming during my college but ended up as a web developer after graduation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>